here are two methods to find the area of
a circle using the method of exhaustion
in the top image we start peeling off
circumferences one at a time and lay
them flat as lines because the
circumference varies linearly with
respect to the radius we see that the
shape will eventually form a triangle in
the bottom diagram we split the circle
into an even number of wedge-shaped
pieces as we create smaller and smaller
wedges we can split the circle apart
into those wedge shaped pieces and glue
the wedges together to form shapes that
look more and more like a rectangle it
turns out that in the top shape we end
up with a triangle that has a height of
R and a base of length 2 pi r and in the
bottom shape we end up with a rectangle
where the length is given by half the
circumference which is pi * R and a
height given by the radius of R so in
the top diagram we get an area of 1 12 *
2i R * R which is p piun r^ 2 and in the
bottom diagram we get an area of piun *
r^ 2 let me know in the comments which
visualization you like better